AMILA WARSHAHENNADI

FRONT END DEVELOPER



CONTACTS

+94719900989

amilawarsha@gmail.com

499/6, 10th Mile Post Road,
Werahara, Boralesgamuwa,
10280, Sri Lanka

LINKS

LinkedIn®:

http://www.linkedin.com/in/ami

l<u>awa</u>

Medium:

https://medium.com/@amilaw

<u>arsha</u>

GitHub:

https://github.com/amilawa

Portfolio:

https://amilawa.github.io/portf

olio/

SKILLS

- Javascript
- React
- HTML
- CSS
- React Native
- AJAX
- JSON
- Android Native
- GIT
- Express.js
- REST APIs

REFERENCES

Prof. Sudantha Liyanage Vice Chancellor

University of Sri Jayewardenepura

T: 0094 714458400 E: suda@sjp.ac.lk

Mr. Sudharshan Welihinda General Manager/Senior Lecturer

Informatics Institute of Technology

T: 0094726868192

E: weli@informaticsholdings.com

ABOUT ME

Enthusiastic Web and Mobile Application Developer with 3+ years of work experience. Motivated, self-starting problem solver with a passion for code and design is also dedicated to lifelong learning. Possess a positive, team-oriented attitude with excellent communication and organizational skills. Seeking to draw on proven software development and engineering skills to increase and improve impressive line of applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer, SyncLeaps Pvt Ltd, 03/2020 - Present

- · Translated the designs and wire-frames into high quality code
- Used understanding of React fundamentals to promote better components lifecycle practices, increasing turnaround speed by 25% with 100% deadline adherence.
- · Good understanding and usage of state and props
- · Comprehensive knowledge of React JS platform and core principles
- Followed documentation to always remain up-to-speed on what needs to be updated in response to new release versions.
- · Command over developing React JS components, Virtual DOM, and workflows
- Technologies and Tools : JavaScript, React, JSON, AJAX, GIT, Visual Studio

Freelancer, Front End Developer (Web and Mobile), 02/2017 - 2020/01

- Developed and maintained React Native components, screens, and features for the mobile applications.
- Implemented custom animations and transitions to flex containers and forms using animation APIs
- Successfully implemented features such as a camera module, push notifications, and a social media login.
- · Implementation of apps and landing pages from concept through deployment
- Experience in customer requirement assessment and understanding.
- Implement a face recognition application using Clarifai API
- Implement the playlist functionality with all features (Similar to iTunes)
- <u>Technologies and Tools</u>: JavaScript, React, React Native, REST, JSON, AJAX, Android Studio, GIT, Visual Studio

Junior Mobile Application Developer, We Are Designers, 08/2014 - 08/2015

- Optimized applications for Android operating systems.
- Provide production support for applications, assist others with problem resolution, and respond with solutions to both functional and technical issues in a timely manner
- Designs, develops, codes, tests, and debugs mobile applications to meet provided user requirements and to address identified defect
- Successfully deployed Android application on Google Play Store
- <u>Technologies and Tools</u>: Java, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Android Native, Eclipse, Android Studio, Visual Studio

EDUCATION

BEng (Hons) Software Engineering, University of Westminster, UK, 2012 - 2016

Graduated as BEng (Hons) in Software Engineering with 2nd Upper degree Awarded **A+ grade** for the final year project

GCE Advanced Level, Mahanama College, Colombo 03, Sri Lanka

AWARDS/CERTIFICATIONS

Diploma in Software Engineering, Informatics Institute of Technology.

JavaScript: Advanced Concepts - ZTM, Udemy

React Native (with Hooks)- ZTM, Udemy

Java, IJSE | Institute of Software Engineering

Web Development (Full Stack Developer) - ZTM, Udemy

Student Coordinator - Seylan Bank PLC

G.C.E O/L and G.C.E A/L (In Commerce)